The world is yours.
Scarface is a action, crime, drama film directed by Brian De Palma.
After getting a green card in exchange for assassinating a Cuban government
official, Tony Montana stakes a claim on the drug trade in Miami.
Viciously murdering anyone who stands in his way, Tony eventually becomes the biggest drug
lord in the state, controlling nearly all the cocaine that comes through Miami.
But increased pressure from the police, wars with Colombian drug cartels and his own
drug-fueled paranoia serve to fuel the flames of his eventual downfall.
Tony Montana, played by Al Pacino.
Manny Ray, played by Steven Bauer.
Elvira, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Gina, played by Mary Elizabeth Mastrantonio.
Frank Lopez, played by Robert Loggia.
Mama Montana, played by Miriam Colon.
Scarface is a 1983 American crime drama film directed by
Brian De Palma, and written by Oliver Stone.
It is a remake of the 1932 film of the same name.
It stars Al Pacino as Cuban refugee Tony Montana, who arrives in Miami
during the Mariel boatlift and becomes a powerful drug lord.
Pacino worked with producer Martin Bregman to develop the project.
Bregman and Sidney Lumet both conceived the idea of
setting the story during the boatlift.
Lumet was initially hired to direct the film but left, feeling that it was
too violent and wanted it to be more of a political film.
De Palma replaced Lumet as director and Bregman hired Stone to write the script.
Stone, who had been struggling with his own cocaine
addiction at the time, wrote the script in Paris.
The film was initially going to be entirely shot in Miami, but the Cuban community denied
requests to film there, feeling that the script portrayed them in a bad light.
Filming took place from November 1982 to May 1983 in
Los Angeles and two weeks in Miami.
The film's soundtrack and score was composed by Giorgio Moroder.
Scarface premiered in New York City on December 1, 1983, and was
released on December 9 by Universal Pictures.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $66 million.
Initial critical response was negative due to its extreme
violence and depiction of stereotypes.
However, in the years that followed, some critics have reappraised it, and it
is now considered to be one of the greatest films ever made.
Screenwriters and directors such as Martin Scorsese have praised the film, and it has been referenced extensively in
pop culture, especially in hip-hop culture, as well as comic books, television programs and video games.
The film is regarded as a cult classic.
The film explores themes of corruption, sibling
relationship, miami, florida, cuba, loss of loved one.
The tone is emotional.